下面是视听时间。
Hi, Mark. I want to have a class party.
Will you help me?
Sure, Alice. So, when shall we have the party?
What about today after class?
No, today is too early.
We have no time to get ready.
Well, let's have it on Friday afternoon.
We won't have any lessons then.
That's great. We can all meet and play party games.
Wonderful! I can play the dance music.
I will bring some balloons and paint some pictures for the party.
Shall we make some food?
Of course. We'd better have different kinds of food.
Then we have to ask Jackson and Lucy for help.
They are good cooks.
That's a good idea.
I will tell them.
Let's get started.
Okay, no problem.
Hi, Mark. I want to have a class party.
Will you help me?
Sure, Alice. So, when shall we have the party?
What about today after class?
No, today is too early.
We have no time to get ready.
Well, let's have it on Friday afternoon.
We won't have any lessons then.
That's great. We can all meet and play party games.
Wonderful! I can play the dance music.
I will bring some balloons and paint some pictures for the party.
Shall we make some food?
Of course. We'd better have different kinds of food.
Then we have to ask Jackson and Lucy for help.
They are good cooks.
That's a good idea.
I will tell them.
Let's get started.
Okay, no problem.
视听结束。
二零二二年，广西北部湾经济区初中学业水平考试。
英语听力考试。
现在开始。
一听力测试。
一听句子，选图片。
你将听到五个句子，请在下列。
六幅图中，选出与所听句子内容相符的图片，并在答题卡上将选定答案的
字母标号涂黑。
每个句子读一遍。
1. I am in class 1, grade 9.
2. Many people like table tennis.
3. It's 9 o 'clock in the
4. The boy sweeps the floor every day.
5. Two students are crossing the road.
二、听句子选答语。
你将听到五个句子，请根据句子内容选择恰当的答语，并在答题卡上。
将选定答案的字母标号涂黑。
每个句子读两遍。
6. Is this your pencil?
7. What's your father's job?
8. How many people are there in your family?
9. You look beautiful today.
Lily 10. It is not healthy to sit for a long time.
10. It is not healthy to sit for a long time.
三听对话，选择最佳答案。
你将听到三段对话，请根据对话内容选出每个问题的最佳答案，并在。答
题卡上将选定答案的字母标号涂黑。
每段对话读两遍。
请听第一段对话，回答第十一至十三小题。
is not healthy sit time.
12. this is Sally speaking.
David, what's up?
Good news! My father sent me a bike this morning.
14. Wonderful! What color is it?
15. It's red and white.
Oh, it's so cool!
Can't wait to see it.
17. Shall we ride to the park now?
18. Great! See you later.
Is that Sally?
Yes, this is Sally speaking.
David, what's up?
Good news! My father sent me a bike this morning.
Wonderful! What color is it?
It's red and white.
Oh, it's so cool!
Can't wait to see it.
Shall we ride to the park now?
Great! See you later.
请听第二段对话，回答第十四至十六小题。
Hello, Mike. What will you do this Saturday?
Hi, Jane. My parents want to climb the mountain.
But I am not sure.
What's your plan?
I plan to make dumplings at home.
Would you like to join me?
That sounds great.
What can I do to help?
I have some vegetables in the fridge.
We need some meat.
How about going to the supermarket to get some meat this Saturday morning?
Good idea. Hello, Mike.
What will you do this Saturday?
Hi, Jane. My parents want to climb the mountain.
But I am not sure.
What's your plan?
I plan to make dumplings at home.
Would you like to join me?
That sounds great.
What can I do to help?
I have some vegetables in the fridge.
We need some meat.
How about going to the supermarket to get some meat this Saturday morning?
Good idea. We'll catch a cold.
请听第三段对话。
回答第十七至二十小题。
Thanks a lot.
Why are you so wet?
What happened? I took a bus to school.
But too many people were on the bus.
And my umbrella is lost.
Sorry to hear that.
Next time, you'd better take care of your things.
Okay, I will.
Thank you for your advice.
You're welcome. Time for class.
Go back to your sit, please.
Good morning, Miss Smith.
Sorry, I'm late.
The rain is too heavy.
It's okay, Tom.
Come and get dried.
Or you will catch a cold.
Thanks a lot.
Why are you so wet?
What happened? I took a bus to school.
But too many people were on the bus.
And my umbrella is lost.
Sorry to hear that.
Next time, you'd better take care of your things.
Okay, I will.
Thank you for your advice.
You're welcome. Time for class.
Go please. Dear Amy,
到你的座位，请。
四听短文，选择最佳答案。
你。
将听到一篇短文，请根据短文内容选出每个问题的最佳答案，并在答题卡
上将选定答案的字母标号涂黑。
短文读两遍。
for your last email.
You asked me about interesting traveling experiences.
I had a trip in northwest China three months ago.
It was so far away from home, and it was deal a wonderful visit.
I stayed there for two weeks.
My uncle has lived there for five years.
When I arrived, he picked me up at the train station.
And he helped me make a trip plan.
On the first day, I took a plane tour over the rocks.
It was so exciting to see the colorful rocks from the sky.
Later, I visited a famous lake.
And I took a boat on it.
Once, when I ate noodles at a restaurant,
I met some friendly local people.
We had a talk about the food, the weather, and many other things.
I felt like we were old friends.
The trip has left lovely and sweet memories in my heart.
How about your interesting experiences?
Waiting for your reply.
Yours, Ellen Dear Amy,
Thanks for your last email.
You asked me about interesting traveling experiences.
I had a trip in northwest China three months ago.
It was so far away from home, and it was deal a wonderful visit.
I stayed there for two weeks.
My uncle has lived there for five years.
When I arrived, he picked me up at the train station.
And he helped me make a trip plan.
On the first day, I took a plane tour over the rocks.
It was so exciting to see the colorful rocks from the sky.
Later, I visited a famous lake.
And I took a boat on it.
Once, when I ate noodles at a restaurant,
I met some friendly local people.
We had a talk about the food, the weather, and many other things.
I felt like we were old friends.
The trip has left lovely and sweet memories in my heart.
How about your interesting experiences?
Waiting for your reply.
Yours, Good morning, everyone.
五、听短文填信息。
你将听到一篇短文，请根据。
短文内容将所缺信息填入答题卡对应的横线上，每空一词。
短文读两遍。
Today, it's my turn to share a with you.
It's called Black Beauty, written by British writer, Anna Sewell.
And the book came out in 1877.
The hero is a horse.
His name is Beauty.
In the book, we can see the world through a horse's eyes.
His first owner raises him with love.
But when he grows up, he is sold.
His new owner does very bad things to him.
And his life gets hard.
My favorite part is the horse's bravest moment.
When his feet touch the first part of the bridge,
he feels the danger.
He stops and doesn't move at all, though his owner hurts him angrily.
In my opinion, his courage saves the lives of many people.
When he makes decisions, he always thinks the needs of people.
So he can be trusted,
even though he can't decide where his life will go.
He still manages to be a brave hero all the time.
Do you want to the book?
Thanks for your listening.
Good morning, everyone.
Today it's my turn to share a with you.
It's called Black Beauty,
written by British writer, Anna Sewell.
And the book came out in 1877.
The hero is a His name is Beauty.
In the book, we can see the world through a horse's eyes.
His first owner raises him with love.
But when he grows up, he is sold.
His new owner does very bad things to him.
And his life gets hard.
My favorite part is the horse's moment.
When his feet touch the first part of the bridge,
he feels the danger.
He stops and doesn't move at all, though his owner hurts him angrily.
In my opinion, his courage saves the lives of many people.
When he makes decisions,
he always thinks the needs of people.
So he can be trusted,
even though he can't decide where his life will go.
He still manages to be a brave hero all the time.
Do you want to read the
Thanks for your listening.
英语听力考试到此结束，请同学们将听力答案转涂到答题卡上，然后继续
做。
笔试部分的题目。